# **ANNIE HWANG - SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

Philadelphia, PA | 484-620-3184 | anniehwang428@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Portfolio

#### **SUMMARY**

Software engineer with a background in therapeutic recreation and restaurant hospitality, with strengths in communication and problem solving. Possesses a strong knowledge of Ruby on Rails and a commitment to performance optimization and best practices in code. Thrives in highly collaborative, fast-paced environments that value continuous innovation to improve the user experience.

#### **SKILLS**

Languages: Ruby, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL Frameworks: Ruby on Rails, React.js, Bootstrap

Databases/Libraries/Tools: Postgres, APIs, Node/npm, Git, GitHub

## **EDUCATION**

# Actualize Coding Bootcamp | Certificate in Full-Stack Web Development

December 2022 - March 2023

A four-month full-stack web development bootcamp. Core technologies included Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, and React.js. Special emphasis on API-driven development, version control with Git, professional tooling, team collaboration, and continual learning.

Temple University | Bachelors of Science in Therapeutic Recreation

May 2022

### **CODING PROJECTS**

Plant Care App - Platform to view care information and save watering schedules for the plants you own. (Repo)

- Backend RESTful API using MVC architecture built with Ruby on Rails.
- Frontend single page application built with npm, webpack, React.js, Bootstrap
- Secure authenticated user profiles using JSON web tokens.

### SonicPi Song Cover - A code-based music creation and performance tool. (Repo)

- Created a synthesizer cover of Song of Storms using SonicPi gem.
- Utilized Ruby language and fundamentals to create a dryer code experience to emulate various musical theory elements, such as repeats, rests, melodies, and chords.

# **EXPERIENCE**

# **Morimoto Starr Restaurant**

November 2022 - Present

#### **Food Runner**

- Collaborate with kitchen and service staff to maintain the highest level of food quality, presentation, and timing in fast paced environments.
- Communicate dish preparation steps, pairing options, and chef's recommendations for each meal presented to a guest.
- Participate in regular process review and quality assurance meetings, contributing knowledge of best practices and industry trends to improve customer experience.

#### Hostess

May 2021 - Present

- Monitored and managed up to 300 reservations a night using OpenTable software, ensuring staffing meets customer expectations and internal standards for employee to guest ratio.
- Coordinated with servers and kitchen staff to ensure smooth communication and timely seating of guests.

### Wesley Enhanced Living PennyPack Park | Activities Aide

January 2022 - May 2022

- Developed and facilitated daily recreational programs in 1:1 and large group settings, for older adults, fostering a positive and inclusive environment.
- Supported participants in utilizing technology or digital platforms for recreational activities.
- Conduct and maintain patient assessments, progress notes, and discharge documentation.